A Guide to the Garber Family Papers, 1871-1985
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Garber Family Papers, 1871-1985
The Library of Virginia
52500
1.35 cu. ft (3 boxes)
Garber Family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Tim Abbott.
Biographical Information
Abraham Garber (1760-1848) was born in York County, Pennsylvania to John H. Garber (1717-1787) and Barbara Miller Garber (1733-1808). Garber moved with his family to Shenandoah Valley, Virginia around 1775, and he spent the remainder of his live in the surrounding area. Garber was a devout member of the Church of the Brethren, and built the congregation's first house of worship in Augusta County. In addition to being a founder of the Middle River Congregation, Garber also served as an elder in the church until his death. Garber married Elizabeth Humbert Garber (1760-1938) and settled with his wife in New Hope, Augusta County on land which came to be known as "Garber Farm". The couple had seven children: John Garber (1792-1854), Daniel Garber (1793-1883), Jacob Garber (1797-1876), Sarah "Sallie" Garber Whitmore (b. 1803), Mary Garber Arion (1805-1864), Samuel Garber (1806-1892), and Esther Garber Stoner (1811-1880).
Scope and Content
Papers, 1871-1985, of the Garber family of Augusta County, Virginia, consist of photograph albums, cabinet card photographs, diaries and scrapbooks, and general papers. The photographs and photograph albums depict members of the Garber and Glick families, their homes and other property, as well as their travels. Scrapbooks contain newspaper clippings relating to the Garber family and the Church of the Brethren, as well Garber genealogical information, handwritten notes, postcards, receipts, and other ephemera. Diaries and other notebooks detail the daily life of 20th century members of the Garber family, and record important familial and local events. General papers include broadsides advertising community events, a program from the 1928 commemoration of Abraham Garber, and papers relating to elections and council meetings of the town of New Hope.
Contents List
- Photograph Album, 1913-1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Photograph Album, 1928-1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Photograph Album, 1935-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Photograph Album, 1942-1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Photographs of children, 1897 and undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Glick Family Reunion photographs, 1909, 1912, and undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Glick Family Reunion photographs, 1910-1925 and undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Photograph of "Grove's House", 1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Photographs of Groups, 1977 and undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Photographs of Cora Garber, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Photograph of Catherine Garber, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Photograph of Cleveland Hildebrand, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Photograph of Ruth and Merle Senger, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Photograph of Owen and Joan, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Photographs of women, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Photograph of Garber house, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Photograph of "Old Swimming Hole", undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Photographs of Horses, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Garber Family Scrapbook, 1775-1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Garber Family Scrapbook, 1719-1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Dickens Birthday Book, 1839-1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Garber Family Ephemera Notebook, 1871-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Composition Notebook, 1906-1964 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Composition Notebook, 1923-1962 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Ada Gardner's Autograph Book, 1925-1947 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Cora V. Garber's Five Year Diary, 1947-1962 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Anonymous Five Year Diary, 1963-1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Anonymous Five Year Diary, 1970-1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Cora V. Garber's Autograph Album undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Town of New Hope papers, 1890 and 1965 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Daniel S. Garber Trustee Sale, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Abraham Garber Commemoration Program, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Community Auction Sale and Supper-New Hope School, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 7)